Ahmed Rushfy Reza

1. No Hair Street, Wari, Dhaka, 1203.

E-mail: ahmed.rushfy.reza@hotmail.com

Mobile: +8801700766870



BRIEF PROFILE

I am an enthusiastic and energetic business graduate. I am currently working in Signify Bangladesh Limited as a Regional Marketing Manager. My previous employers were New Zealand Dairy Products Bangladesh LTD, Intertek and Transcom Electronics LTD. I have experience in Trade Marketing, Channel Development, Trade development within the fixed schedule to fulfil my target.

CAREER OBJECTIVE

To succeed in an environment of growth and excellence and earn a job which provide me job satisfaction, and self-development and help me achieve organizational goal as well as personal.

EXPERIENCE



1. Name of the company: Signify Bangladesh LTD
Formerly known as Philips Lighting Bangladesh LTD

Signify is a global market leader with recognized expertise in the development, manufacturing & application of innovative (LED) lighting solutions.

Tenure: August 2017 – Till Date

Designation: Regional Marketing Manager/Channel Marketeer

Job Responsibilities:

Responsible for the entire channel marketing activities of Bangladesh and Sri Lanka. That includes:

- 1. Channel and trade development by initiating trade scheme/incentive scheme and retailer and channel partners activation.
- 2. Creating provision out of product pricing, maintaining the same in the system and disburse the provision as per market requirement.
- 3. To set channel strategy to ensure channel hygiene and availability of product to the trade channel and to increase depth of product distribution.
- 4. Product planning and placing material requisition to ensure proper buffer stock and efficient service plan.
- 5. Analytics to identify product movement/market dynamics and implementation to enhance channel health.
- 6. Initiating strategies to improve the distribution of remote areas where distribution is a challenge.
- 7. Initiating Secondary SKU wise sales tracking and monitoring product movement and controlling the field force and take development action where necessary.
- 8. New product launching and developing existing product lines to develop retail channel volume.
- 9. Initiating BTL drives to ensure brand communications and brand visibility to rural, semi urban, urban areas.
- 10. MARCOM activities to increase brand awareness to enhance product offtake.



2. Name of the company: New Zealand Dairy Products Bangladesh LTD

New Zealand Dairy Products Bangladesh LTD is one of the biggest and renowned FMCG Company operating its business in Bangladesh since 1992. It has a rich heritage in the dairy industry in terms of quality of products and business operations. Its mission is to delight consumers through dairy products that are nutritious, innovative, and taste great. It is serving quality dairy products like Diploma, Red Cow, and Shape up etc and non - dairy products like Doodles, Poppers and Detos.

Tenure: December 2014 – July 2017

Designation: Senior Trade Marketing Executive

Job Responsibilities:

- 1. Brand Activation/Event Management by Planning and set a defined module of an event to relate the event/activation with the brand and successfully executing the same. Experiences Dhaka International Trade Fair, Retailer Conference, Chef/Client Conference, Door to Door, School Activation, Market Drive, Wet Sampling, Dry Sampling, and Region Based Activation and events etc.
- 2. Merchandising (General Trade) that includes leading and monitoring a team of 52 Contact Merchandisers, 10 Supervisors to execute portfolio display program in retail outlets and 5 merchandisers, 10 brand promoters in modern retails.
- 3. Modern Trade Promo Management, that includes Promo Negotiation and Finalization with client. Examples Eid Offer with Shwapno. FSU/Gondola agreement, execution and payment management and POSM Management (Planning, Designing, Budgeting, Executing, Monitoring).
- 4. Target Setting of Modern Trade Sales operation Team Monthly Target up to Client type wise/ SKU Wise/Volume/Value

3. Name of the company: **Intertek**.

Intertek
Valued Quality. Delivered.

Intertek is a leading quality solutions provider to industries worldwide. From auditing and inspection, to testing, training, advisory, quality assurance and certification, Intertek adds value for its customers by helping improve the quality and safety of their products, assets and processes with a network of more than 1,000 laboratories and offices and over 36,000 people in more than 100 countries.

Tenure: January 2014 - December 2014

Designation: **Business Development Officer** Job Responsibilities:

- 1. Managing accounts and meeting targets related to revenue growth, profit margin, and customer retention.
- 2. Strategically planning for obtaining new business, continuing and expanding current business.
- 3. Effectively implementing sales, marketing, and customer service as specific and assigned area.
- 4. Regularly monitoring, analyzing, and reviewing activity reports and recommending improvement action as appropriate and feedback to senior management about marketplace and competitors' activity.
- 5. Following up, tracking and reporting target versus actual performance and achievement of all designated customers.
- 6. To prepare and submit monthly performance analysis of Key Account Team, Business Development Team and Buyer wise, Supplier wise, Agent wise sales analysis



4. Name of the company: Transcom Electronics LTD

Transcom Group Limited is a Bangladeshi business conglomerate. The businesses under this group include Beverage, Pharmaceuticals, Newspaper, Radio channel, Electronics, Foods etc. This group employs more than 10000 people. Transcom Group is one of the oldest and biggest companies in Bangladesh.

Tenure: August 2011 – December 2013

Designation: Marketing Officer (Transcom Lighting Business)

Job Responsibilities:

- 1. Assist to design monthly sales target and distributor wise trade promotion target.
- 2. Assist to design Trade Promotion, Long Term Promotions, Slab Program, Article Scheme, and Loyalty Program of Transcom Lighting Business.
- 3. To evaluate and calculate promotional schemes of Transcom Lighting and also preparing report, gift disbursement and make proper adjustment.
- 4. Filed visit on regular basis.

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration, 2013 **United International University** Concentration: Human Resource Management

CGPA: 3.19

Bachelor of Business Administration, 2010

East West UniversityConcentration: Marketing
CGPA: 3.12

Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC), 2005

Dhaka City College

Concentration: Business Studies

GPA: 4.80

Secondary School Certificate (SSC), 2003 **Motijheel Model High School & College**

Concentration: Business Studies

GPA: 4.19

PERSONAL DETAILS

Father's Name : Late Md. Nur HossainMother's Name : Mrs. Roksana Hossain

Date of birth : June, 05, 1988
Religion : Islam (Sunni)
Blood Group : A (Positive)
Nationality : Bangladeshi
Marital Status : Married

REFERENCES

Mr. Saleh Uddin Bhuiyan Head of Marketing IFAD Multi Products & Home Care LTD

Phone: +8801914885911

E-mail: saleh.uddin@implbd.com

Ashraful Ehsan Head of Sales and Trade Marketging Cavinkare Bangladesh

Phone: +8801713092455

E-mail: ashrafulehsan@cavinkare.com